Italian Painting Photograph Collection
Yale University Arts Library
- M (Box 118)
  - Miscellaneous Artists M., 83 (Box 118)
    - Manzuoli, Tommaso d'Antonio, 1536-1571., 1 (Box 118)
    - Marasco, Antonio, 1896-., 1 (Box 118)
    - Marchesi da Cotignola, Girolamo, c.1481-1540., 1 (Box 118)
    - Marconi, Rocco, XVI C., 3 (Box 118)
    - Maria, Astolfo de, XX C., 1 (Box 118)
    - Martinelli, Giovanni, 1610-1659., 1 (Box 118)
    - Marussig, Piero, 1879-1937., 2 (Box 118)
    - Massari, Michele, 1902-1954., 1 (Box 118)
    - Masteletta, 1575-1655., 1 (Box 118)
    - Matteo da Gualdo, active 1468., 3 (Box 118)
    - Mazone, Giovanni, 1433-1512., 1 (Box 118)
    - Mazzola-Bedoli, Girolamo, c.1500-1569., 2 (Box 118)
    - Mazzoni, Giulio, 1525-1618., 1 (Box 118)
    - Mazzuoli, Giuseppe, 1536-1589., 1 (Box 118)
      Also known as Il Bastarolo.
    - Meacci, Ricciardo, 1856-., 2 (Box 118)
    - Melanzio, Francesco, XVI C., 2 (Box 118)
    - Meloni, Altobello, active 1497-1517., 1 (Box 118)
    - Melzi, Francesco, 1498-1570., 2 (Box 118)
    - Merz, Mario, 1925-., 1 (Box 118)
    - Meucci, Vincenzo, 1699-1766., 1 (Box 118)
    - Michetti, Francesco Paolo, 1851-1929., 3 (Box 118)
    - Milena (Barilli), 1912-., 1 (Box 118)
    - Minardi, Tommaso, 1787-1871., 1 (Box 118)
    - Mitelli, Agostino, 1609-1660., 2 (Box 118)
    - Molinari, Antonio, 1665-1735., 1 (Box 118)
    - Montanari, Giuseppe, 1889-., 1 (Box 118)
    - Monte da Bologna, XIV C., 4 (Box 118)
    - Montelatici, Francesco, 1600-1661., 2 (Box 118)
    - Montorfano, Giovanni Donato, 1440-1510., 2 (Box 118)
    - Morazzone, Pier Francesco, 1571-1626., 4 (Box 118)
    - Morbelli, Angelo, 1863-1919., 1 (Box 118)
    - Morelli, Domenico, 1826-1901., 2 (Box 118)
    - Morlotti, Ennio, 1910-., 2 (Box 118)
    - Morone, Francesco, c.1471-1529., 3 (Box 118)
    - Munari, Christofero, 1667-1720., 1 (Box 118)
    - Mussini, Luigi, 1813-1888., 2 (Box 118)
    - Muzzioli, Giovanni, 1854-1894., 1 (Box 118)
  - Individual Artists M., 1708 (Box 118)
    - Macchiavelli, Zanobi, 1418-1479., 3 (Box 118)
    - Magnasso, Alessandro, 1681-1749., 49 (Box 118)
      - Drawings., 4 (Box 119)
      - Paintings., 45 (Box 120)
    - Mainardi, Sebastiano, active 1474-1513., 16 (Box 120)
    - Manetti, Rutilio, 1571-1639., 10 (Box 120)
    - Manfredi, Bartolomeo, 1580-1620., 7 (Box 120)
    - Manni, Giannicola di Paolo, 1493-1544., 3 (Box 120)
    - Mannozzi, Giovanni, 1592-1636., 7 (Box 120)
    - Mansueti, Giovanni di Niccolo, 1485-1527., 6 (Box 120)
    - Mantegna, Andrea, 1431-1506., 209 (Box 120)
      - Drawings., 19 (Box 120)
      - Paintings., 190 (Box 120)
        - Locations not noted., 6 (Box 121)
        - Miscellaneous cities., 40 (Box 121-, Box 122)
        - Berlin., 6 (Box 122)
        - Florence., 14 (Box 122)
        - London., 13 (Box 122)
        - Mantua., 36 (Box 122)
          - General subjects., 9 (Box 122)
          - The Court of Ludovico Gonzaga., 8 (Box 122)
          - The Return of Cardinal Gonzaga., 19 (Box 122)
        - Milan., 11 (Box 122)
        - New York., 13 (Box 122)
        - Padua., 15 (Box 123)
        - Paris., 19 (Box 123)
        - Verona., 8 (Box 123)
        - Washington, D.C., 9 (Box 123)
    - Maratti, Carlo, 1625-1713., 29 (Box 123)
      - Drawings., 6 (Box 123)
      - Paintings., 23 (Box 123)
    - Margaritone d'Arezzo, 1216-1293., 8 (Box 123)
    - Mariani, Carlo Maria, 1931-., 1 (Box 123)
    - Marieschi, Michele, 1693-1743., 11 (Box 124)
    - Marini, Marino, 1901-1980., 7 (Box 124)
    - Mariotto di Nardo, active 1393-1424., 5 (Box 124)
    - Martino di Bartolommeo, active 1387-1434., 10 (Box 124)
    - Marziale, Marco, 1489-1507., 4 (Box 124)
    - Masaccio, Tommaso Guidi, 1401-1428., 139 (Box 124)
      - Miscellaneous locations or location not noted., 9 (Box 124)
      - Berlin., 12 (Box 124)
      - Florence., 93 (Box 124)
        - Miscellaneous locations., 1 (Box 125)
        - S. Maria del Carmine, Brancacci Chapel., 58 (Box 125-, Box 126)
        - S. Maria Novella., 22 (Box 126)
        - Uffizi., 12 (Box 126)
      - London., 19 (Box 126)
      - Naples., 6 (Box 126)
    - Maso di Banco, active 1360-1346., 19 (Box 126)
    - Masolino, Tommaso, 1383-1447., 109 (Box 126)
      - Miscellaneous locations., 14 (Box 126)
      - Castiglione D'Olona., 30 (Box 127)
      - Empoli., 25 (Box 127)
      - Florence., 11 (Box 127)
      - London., 6 (Box 127)
      - Naples., 11 (Box 127)
      - Rome., 12 (Box 128)
    - Matteis, Paolo de, 1662-1728., 10 (Box 128)
    - Matteo di Giovanni, 1435-1495., 57 (Box 128)
      - Miscellaneous locations., 23 (Box 128)
      - Siena., 34 (Box 129)
    - Mazzola, Filippo, c.1460-1505., 3 (Box 129)
    - Mazzolino, Ludovico, c.1478-1528., 9 (Box 129)
    - Melozzo da Forli, 1438-1499., 33 (Box 129)
    - Memmi, Lippo, active 1317-1357., 32 (Box 129)
    - Menabuoi, Giusto di Giovanni de, -1393., 4 (Box 129)
    - Mezzastri, Pier-Antonio, 1437-1506., 7 (Box 129)
    - Michelangelo Buonarroti, 1475-1564., 539 (Box 129)
      - Portraits of Michelangelo., 5 (Box 130)
      - Drawings., 189 (Box 130)
        - Studies of general subjects., 80 (Box 130)
          - Miscellaneous subjects., 4 (Box 130)
          - Figures., 42 (Box 130)
          - Heads., 34 (Box 131)
        - Studies of specific subjects., 109 (Box 131)
          - Miscellaneous subjects., 17 (Box 131)
          - Designs for tombs., 8 (Box 131)
          - Madonnas., 11 (Box 132)
          - Passion scenes and crucifixions., 27 (Box 132)
          - Studies for the Sistine Chapel., 46 (Box 133)
      - Paintings., 345 (Box 133)
        - Miscellaneous locations., 3 (Box 133)
        - Florence., 11 (Box 133)
        - London., 6 (Box 133)
        - Rome., 325 (Box 133)
          - Pauline Chapel, Vatican., 11 (Box 133)
          - Sistine Chapel, Vatican., 314 (Box 133)
            - General views and views of cleaning process., 8 (Box 133)
            - Sectional views., 15 (Box 134)
            - Ancestors of Christ., 59 (Box 134)
            - Caryatids and putti., 19 (Box 134)
            - Corner vaults., 8 (Box 134)
            - Center scenes., 61 (Box 134)
              - Miscellaneous scenes., 19 (Box 135)
              - Creation of Adam., 19 (Box 135)
              - Creation of Eve., 7 (Box 135)
              - Temptation and expulsion., 10 (Box 135)
              - Deluge., 6 (Box 135)
            - Ignudi., 52 (Box 136)
            - Medallions., 7 (Box 136)
            - Prophets., 40 (Box 136)
            - Sibyls., 25 (Box 136)
            - Last Judgement., 20 (Box 137)
    - Michele da Verona, c.1470-1536/44., 4 (Box 137)
    - Michelino, Domenico di, 1417-1491., 4 (Box 137)
    - Modigliani, Amedeo, 1884-1920., 146 (Box 137)
      - Miscellany., 1 (Box 137)
      - Drawings., 9 (Box 137)
      - Paintings., 136 (Box 137)
        - Miscellaneous subjects/group portraits., 4 (Box 137)
        - Men., 34 (Box 138)
        - Women., 75 (Box 138-, Box 139)
        - Nudes., 23 (Box 139)
    - Mola, Pier Francesco, 1612-1666., 10 (Box 139)
    - Monsu Desiderio, active 1617-1631., 10 (Box 139)
    - Montagna, Bartolommeo, 1450-1523., 30 (Box 139)
      - Miscellaneous locations and locations not noted., 23 (Box 139)
      - Padua., 7 (Box 139)
    - Moranda, Paolo, c.1486-1522., 5 (Box 139)
      Also known as Cavazzola.
    - Morandi, Giorgio, 1890-1964., 32 (Box 139)
    - Moretto da Brescia, 1498-1555., 49 (Box 139)
      - Drawings., 2 (Box 139)
      - Paintings., 47 (Box 140)
        - Miscellaneous locations., 26 (Box 140)
        - Brescia., 12 (Box 140)
        - New York., 9 (Box 140)
    - Morone, Domenico, 1442-1503., 6 (Box 140)
    - Moroni, Giovanni Battista, c.1525-1578., 49 (Box 140)
      - Miscellaneous locations and locations not noted., 22 (Box 140)
      - Bergamo., 11 (Box 140)
      - London., 11 (Box 141)
      - New York., 5 (Box 141)
    - Mura, Francesco de, 1698-1728., 15 (Box 141)
    - Muziano, Girolamo, 1528/32-1592., 2 (Box 141)
- N (Box 141)
  - Miscellaneous Artists N., 17 (Box 141)
    - Nannetti, Neri, 1890-., 1 (Box 141)
    - Nannini, Mario, 1895-1918., 2 (Box 141)
    - Natali, Renato, 1883-., 1 (Box 141)
    - Nazari, Bartolommeo, 1699-1758., 2 (Box 141)
    - Niccolo di Buonaccorso, -1388., 1 (Box 141)
    - Niccolo di Pietro Gerini, 1394-1409., 3 (Box 141)
    - Niccolo di Segna, active 1330-1345., 2 (Box 141)
    - Nono, Luigi, 1850-1918., 1 (Box 141)
    - Notte, Emilio, 1891-., 1 (Box 141)
    - Novelli, Pietro, 1603-1677., 3 (Box 141)
  - Individual Artists N., 94 (Box 142)
    - Nardo di Cione, active 1345-1366., 24 (Box 142)
    - Nelli, Ottaviano, 1370/75-1444., 8 (Box 142)
    - Neri di Bicci, 1419-1491., 22 (Box 142)
    - Niccolo da Fogliano, c.1430-1502., 7 (Box 142)
    - Niccolo di Tommaso, active 1343-1376., 8 (Box 142)
    - Nittis, Giuseppe de, 1846-1884., 17 (Box 142)
    - Nuzi, Allegretto, active 1346-1366., 8 (Box 142)
- O (Box 142)
  - Miscellaneous Artists O, 15 (Box 142)
    - Odazzi, Giovanni, 1663-1731., 1 (Box 142)
    - Oppi, Ubaldo, XX C., 1 (Box 142)
    - Oriolo, Giovanni, XV C., 1 (Box 142)
    - Orlandi, Deodato, -c.1337., 4 (Box 142)
    - Orsi, Lelio, 1511-1587., 3 (Box 142)
    - Ortolano, Giovanni Battista, 1487-1527., 5 (Box 142)
  - Individual Artists O., 23 (Box 142)
    - Oggiono, Marco da, c.1470-1540., 11 (Box 143)
    - Orcagna, Andrea di Cione, 1308-1368., 12 (Box 143)
- P (Box 143)
  - Miscellaneous Artists P., 85 (Box 143)
    - Pacino di Buonaguida, active 1310., 4 (Box 143)
    - Pagani, Gregorio, 1558-1605., 1 (Box 143)
    - Pagani, Vincenzo, c.1490-1568., 1 (Box 143)
    - Pagliei, Gioacchino, 1852-1896., 1 (Box 143)
    - Palizzi, Filippo, 1818-1899., 2 (Box 143)
    - Palizzi, Giuseppe, 1813-1888., 1 (Box 143)
    - Panetti, Domenico, c.1460-1513., 1 (Box 143)
    - Pannaggi, Ivo, 1901-., 4 (Box 143)
    - Panter, Gea, XX C., 1 (Box 143)
    - Paoletti, Antonio, 1834-1912., 1 (Box 143)
    - Paolini, Pietro, 1603-1681., 2 (Box 143)
    - Paresce, Renato, 1886-1937., 1 (Box 143)
    - Parmigianino, Michele, 1671-1751/57., 1 (Box 143)
    - Passarotti, Bartolomeo, 1529-1592., 4 (Box 143)
    - Passeri, Giuseppe, c.1634-1714., 2 (Box 143)
    - Passignano, Domenico Cresti da, 1560-1636., 2 (Box 143)
    - Pellegrini, Domenico, 1759-1840., 1 (Box 143)
    - Pellegrino da San Daniele, 1460/70-1547., 1 (Box 143)
    - Pellicciaio, Jacopodi Mino del, 1362-1398., 3 (Box 143)
    - Pellizza da Volpedo, Giuseppe, 1868-1907., 5 (Box 143)
    - Pennacchi, Pier Maria, 1464-1528., 4 (Box 143)
    - Pesello, Guiliano, 1367-1446., 1 (Box 143)
    - Piazza da Lodi, Albertino, 1490-1528., 1 (Box 143)
    - Piazza da Lodi, Martino, -1527., 1 (Box 143)
    - Pier di Lorenzo Pratese, 1413-1487., 1 (Box 143)
    - Pietro da Rimini, active 1328., 2 (Box 143)
    - Pietro da Saliba, active c.1500., 2 (Box 143)
    - Pietro della Vecchia, 1605-1678., 1 (Box 143)
    - Pietro di Giovanni, active 1428-1438., 1 (Box 143)
    - Pietro di Lorenzo, XV C., 1 (Box 143)
    - Pietro di Martino, 1435-1515., 1 (Box 143)
    - Pietro de Miniato, 1366-1450., 3 (Box 143)
    - Pinelli, Bartolomeo, 1781-1835., 1 (Box 143)
    - Piola, Domenico, 1627-1703., 2 (Box 143)
    - Pisa, Giovanni da, XV C., 2 (Box 143)
    - Pistoletto, Michelangelo, 1933-., 2 (Box 143)
    - Pizzolo, Niccolo, active 1421-1453., 1 (Box 143)
    - Po, Giacomo del, 1652-1726., 1 (Box 143)
    - Polidoro de Renzi da Lanciano, 1515-1565., 1 (Box 143)
    - Polinori, Andrea, active c.1612-1642., 1 (Box 143)
    - Poppi, Il, 1544-1597., 1 (Box 143)
      Also known as Francesco Morandini.
    - Prampolini, Enrico, 1894-1956., 2 (Box 143)
    - Previati, Gaetano, 1852-1920., 1 (Box 143)
    - Priamo di Piero della Quercia. 1438-1467., 2 (Box 143)
    - Pruna, Pedro, 1904-., 1 (Box 143)
    - Puccinelli, Angelo, active 1380-1407., 1 (Box 143)
    - Puccini, Mario, XX C., 1 (Box 143)
    - Puligo, Domenico, 1492-1527., 2 (Box 143)
    - Pulzone, Scipione, 1550-1588., 2 (Box 143)
      Also known as Il Gaetano.
    - Pupino delle Lame, Biagio, active 1511-1575., 1 (Box 143)
    - Purificato, Domenico, 1915-., 1 (Box 143)
  - Individual Artists P., 1485 (Box 143)
    - Pacchia, Girolamo del, 1477-1535., 5 (Box 143)
    - Pacchiarotto, Giacomo, 1474-1540., 12 (Box 144)
    - Padovani, Gualtiero, XVI C., 29 (Box 144)
    - Pagani, Enzo, 1920-., 4 (Box 144)
    - Palma Il Giovane, Jacopo, 1544-1628., 8 (Box 144)
    - Palma Vecchio, 1480-1528., 42 (Box 144)
      - Miscellaneous locations., 14 (Box 144)
      - Dresden., 9 (Box 144)
      - Venice., 19 (Box 145)
    - Palmezzano, Marco, 1456-1537., 11 (Box 145)
    - Pannini, Giovanni Paolo, 1691-1765., 66 (Box 145)
      - Drawings., 7 (Box 145)
      - Paintings., 59 (Box 145)
        - Locations not noted., 9 (Box 145)
        - Miscellaneous cities., 28 (Box 145)
        - Boston., 7 (Box 145)
        - New York., 6 (Box 145)
        - Rome., 9 (Box 146)
    - Paolo di Giovanni Fei, active 1372-1410., 15 (Box 146)
    - Paolo Veneziano, 1333-1362., 14 (Box 146)
    - Parentino, Bernardino, 1437-1531., 6 (Box 146)
    - Parmigianino, Francesco, 1503-1540., 65 (Box 146)
      - Drawings., 22 (Box 147)
      - Paintings., 43 (Box 147)
    - Pasini, Roberto, 1826-1899., 4 (Box 147)
    - Pedrini, Giovanni, active 1520-1540., 7 (Box 147)
      Also known as Giampietrino.
    - Pellegrini, Giovanni Antonio, 1675-1741., 7 (Box 147)
    - Penni, Francesco, 1488-1528., 2 (Box 148)
    - Perugino, Pietro Vanucci, 1446-1528., 219 (Box 148)
      - Drawings., 20 (Box 148)
      - Paintings., 199 (Box 148)
        - Miscellaneous locations or locations not noted., 41 (Box 149)
        - Florence., 47 (Box 149)
        - London., 11 (Box 149)
        - Paris., 9 (Box 150)
        - Perugia., 55 (Box 151)
        - Rome., 24 (Box 151)
        - Washington, D.C., 12 (Box 151)
    - Peruzzi, Baldassare, 1481-1536., 29 (Box 151)
      - Drawings., 7 (Box 151)
      - Paintings., 22 (Box 152)
    - Pesellino, Francesco di Stefano, 1422-1457., 62 (Box 152)
    - Piazzetta, Giovanni Battista, 1682-1754., 40 (Box 152)
      - Drawings., 17 (Box 153)
      - Paintings., 23 (Box 153)
    - Pier Francesco Fiorentino, active 1470-1500., 16 (Box 153)
    - Piero di Cosimo, 1462-1521., 111 (Box 153)
      - Locations not noted., 2 (Box 154)
      - Miscellaneous cities., 62 (Box 154-, Box 155)
      - Florence., 10 (Box 155)
      - London., 17 (Box 155)
      - Rome., 18 (Box 155)
      - School of Piero di Cosimo., 2 (Box 155)
    - Pietro di Domenico, 1457-1506., 5 (Box 155)
    - Pietro di Domenico da Montepulciano, c.1350., 2 (Box 155)
    - Pinturicchio, 1454-1513., 173 (Box 155)
      - Drawings., 5 (Box 155)
      - Paintings., 168 (Box 155)
        - Miscellaneous locations and locations not noted., 21 (Box 155)
        - Perugia., 10 (Box 155)
        - Rome., 84 (Box 155)
          - Miscellaneous locations., 11 (Box 155)
          - S. Maria del Popolo, 18 (Box 156)
          - Vatican., 55 (Box 157)
        - Siena., 46 (Box 157)
        - Spello., 7 (Box 158)
    - Piombo, Sebastiano del, 1485-1547., 55 (Box 158)
      - Drawings., 8 (Box 158)
      - Paintings., 47 (Box 159)
    - Piranesi, Giovanni Battista, 1720-1778., 18 (Box 159)
    - Pisanello, Antonio, 1395-1456., 40 (Box 159)
      - Drawings., 25 (Box 159)
      - Paintings., 15; paintings (Box 160)
    - Pisis, Filippo de, 1896-1956., 9 (Box 160)
    - Pittoni, Giovanni Battista, 1687-1767., 7 (Box 160)
    - Poccetti, Bernardino, 1541-1612., 5 (Box 160)
    - Polidoro da Caravaggio, 1493-1543., 6 (Box 161)
    - Pollaiuolo, Antonio, 1429-1498., 73 (Box 161)
      - Drawings., 19 (Box 161)
      - Paintings., 54 (Box 161)
    - Pollaiuolo, Piero, 1443-1496., 14 (Box 161)
    - Ponte, Giovanni del, 1358-1437., 7 (Box 161)
    - Pontormo, Jacopo da, 1494-1557., 165 (Box 161)
      - Drawings., 57 (Box 161)
      - Paintings., 108 (Box 161)
        - Miscellaneous locations and locations not noted., 46 (Box 161)
        - Boldone., 11 (Box 161)
        - Carmiginano., 6 (Box 161)
        - Florence., 34 (Box 161)
        - London., 7 (Box 161)
        - Paris., 4 (Box 161)
    - Pordenone, Giovanni Antonio, 1484-1539., 24 (Box 161)
      - Drawings., 9 (Box 161)
      - Paintings., 15 (Box 161)
    - Pozzo, Andrea, 1642-1709., 14 (Box 161)
    - Predis, Ambrogio da, c.1455-1506., 18 (Box 161)
    - Preti, Mattia, 1613-1699., 47 (Box 161)
    - Previtali, Andrea, 1470-1528., 7 (Box 161)
    - Primaticcio, Francesco, 1504-1570., 15 (Box 161)
    - Procaccini, G.C., 1570-1625., 7 (Box 162)
- Q (Box 162)
  - Miscellaneous Artists Q., 1 (Box 162)
    - Quartararo, Ricardo, 1443-1506., 1 (Box 162)
- R (Box 162)
  - Miscellaneous Artists R., 20 (Box 162)
    - Raffaellino da Reggio, 1550-1578., 2 (Box 162)
    - Ranzoni, Daniele, 1843-1889., 1 (Box 162)
    - Rico, Martin, 1833-1908., 1 (Box 162)
    - Roberti, Domenico, 1642-1707., 3 (Box 162)
    - Roncalli, Cristofano, 1551-1626., 1 (Box 162)
    - Rondinelli, Niccolo, active1480-1500., 4 (Box 162)
    - Rosa, Francesco di, 1600-1654., 1 (Box 162)
    - Rosi, Alessandro, c.1627-1707., 1 (Box 162)
    - Rosseli, Matteo, 1578-1650., 1 (Box 162)
    - Rossi, Luigi, 1853-1923., 1 (Box 162)
    - Rossi, Mariano Pasquale, 1641-1725., 1 (Box 162)
    - Rubiales, Pedro de, XVI C., 1 (Box 162)
    - Ruppoli, Giuseppe, 1600-1659., 1 (Box 162)
    - Russolo, Luigi, 1885-1947., 1 (Box 162)
  - Individual Artists R., 1144 (Box 162)
    - Raibolini, Francesco, c.1450-1517., 66 (Box 163)
      Also known as Il Francia.
    - Raphael Sanzio, 1483-1520., 713 (Box 163)
      - Drawings., 205 (Box 163)
        - Locations not noted., 18 (Box 163)
        - Miscellaneous cities., 25 (Box 163)
        - Chatsworth., 16 (Box 164)
        - Florence., 25 (Box 164)
        - Lille., 13 (Box 164)
        - London., 29 (Box 164)
          - General subjects., 14 (Box 164)
          - Tapestry cartoons., 15 (Box 165)
        - Oxford., 25 (Box 165)
        - Paris., 15 (Box 165)
        - Vienna., 23 (Box 165)
        - Windsor., 16 (Box 166)
      - Paintings., 508 (Box 166)
        - Locations not noted., 12 (Box 166)
        - Miscellaneous cities., 51 (Box 166)
        - Dresden., 9 (Box 167)
        - Florence., 57 (Box 167)
        - London., 26 (Box 168)
        - Madrid., 15 (Box 168)
        - Milan., 16 (Box 168)
        - Munich., 7 (Box 168)
        - Naples., 11 (Box 168)
        - New York., 6 (Box 168)
        - Paris., 20 (Box 169)
        - Rome., 248 (Box 169)
          - Miscellaneous locations., 14 (Box 169)
          - Borghese Gallery., 10 (Box 169)
          - Villa Farnesina., 24 (Box 169)
          - Vatican., 200 (Box 169)
            - Miscellaneous works., 10 (Box 169)
            - The Transfiguration., 11 (Box 170)
            - Stanza d'Eliodoro., 22 (Box 170)
            - Stanza del Incendio., 17 (Box 170)
            - Stanza della Segnatura., 67 (Box 171)
            - Raphael's Loggia., 73 (Box 172)
        - Washington, D.C., 22 (Box 172)
        - School of Raphael., 8 (Box 172)
    - Reni, Guido, 1575-1692., 167 (Box 172)
      - Drawings., 11 (Box 172)
      - Paintings., 156 (Box 172)
        - Locations not noted or private collections., 23 (Box 173)
        - Miscellaneous cities., 51 (Box 173)
        - Bologna., 19 (Box 173)
        - London., 11 (Box 173)
        - Paris., 5 (Box 174)
        - Rome., 47 (Box 174)
    - Ricci, Marco, 1676-1729., 10 (Box 174)
    - Ricci, Sebastiano, 1659-1734., 28 (Box 174)
      - Drawings., 4 (Box 174)
      - Paintings., 24 (Box 175)
    - Roberti, Ercole de, 1430-1496., 29 (Box 175)
    - Roberto Oderisi, XIV C., 5 (Box 175)
    - Romanino, Girolamo, 1485-1566., 16 (Box 175)
    - Rosa, Salvator, 1615-1673., 37 (Box 176)
    - Rosselli, Cosimo, 1439-1507., 26 (Box 176)
    - Rossello di Jacopo Franchi, 1376-1457., 5 (Box 176)
    - Rossini, Pellegrino di Mariano, active 1449-1492., 2 (Box 176)
    - Rosso, Il, 1494-1540., 35 (Box 177)
      Also known as Rosso Fiorentino.
    - Rotari, Pietro, 1707-1762., 5 (Box 177)
- S (Box 177)
  - Miscellaneous Artists S., 44 (Box 177)
    - Sacchi, Andrea, 1599-1661., 2 (Box 177)
    - Sacchi, Pier Francesco, active 1512-1527., 2 (Box 177)
    - Sala, P. 1859-1924., 1 (Box 177)
    - Saliba, Antonello da, active 1485-1528., 1 (Box 177)
    - Salietti, Alberto, 1892-., 1 (Box 177)
    - Salimbena, Ventura, 1567-1613., 1 (Box 177)
    - Salviati, Giuseppe, 1518-1585., 1 (Box 177)
    - San Gallo, Antonio da, XVI C., 1 (Box 177)
    - Santomaso, Giuseppe, 1907-., 1 (Box 177)
    - Sartorio, Aristide, 1861-1932., 1 (Box 177)
    - Savinio, Alberto, 1891-1952., 2 (Box 177)
    - Scacco, Cristoforo, 1483-1500., 1 (Box 177)
      Also known as Scacco da Verona.
    - Scaletti, Leonardo, active 1484., 3 (Box 177)
    - Schiavo, Paolo, 1397-1452., 1 (Box 177)
    - Semitecolo, Niccolo, active 1367-1370., 1 (Box 177)
    - Sernesi, Raffaello, 1838-1866., 3 (Box 177)
    - Serodine, Giovanni, 1594-1630., 1 (Box 177)
    - Simone dei Crocefissi, XIV C., 1 (Box 177)
    - Sirani, Elisabetta, 1638-1665., 1 (Box 177)
    - Soffici, Ardegno, 1879-1964., 1 (Box 177)
    - Soggi, Niccolo, 1474-1554., 2 (Box 177)
    - Soldati, Atanasio, 1896-1953., 1 (Box 177)
    - Sole, Giovan Gioseffo dal, 1654-1719., 2 (Box 177)
    - Sorbi, Giovanni, 1695-., 1 (Box 177)
    - Spadini, Armando, 1883-1915., 1 (Box 177)
    - Spiglio, Julio, 1924-., 1 (Box 177)
    - Spinelli, Parri, 1387-1453., 1 (Box 177)
    - Stangioni, XVIII C., 1 (Box 177)
    - Starnina, Gherardo, 1354-1408., 2 (Box 177)
    - Stefano di Giovanni da Verona, 1375-1451., 2 (Box 177)
    - Stefano Veneziano, XIV C., 2 (Box 177)
    - Stradone, Giovanni, 1911-., 1 (Box 177)
  - Individual Artists S., 1265 (Box 177)
    - Sabatelli, Luigi, 1772-1850., 2 (Box 177)
    - Sacchi, Andrea, 1594/9-1661., 14 (Box 177)
    - Salimbeni, Lorenzo and Jacopo, XV C., 4 (Box 178)
    - Salvi, Giovanni Battista, 1609-1685., 26 (Box 178)
    - Salviati, Francesco, 1510-1563., 18 (Box 179)
    - Sano di Pietro, 1406-1481., 74 (Box 179)
      - Miscellaneous cities., 23 (Box 179)
      - New Haven., 7 (Box 179)
      - New York., 6 (Box 179)
      - Siena., 38 (Box 179)
    - Santa Croce, Girolamo di, 1480(?)-1557., 4 (Box 179)
    - Santarelli, G.A., 1758-1826., 9 (Box 179)
    - Santi, Giovanni, 1430-1494., 6 (Box 179)
    - Saraceni, Carlo, 1585-1620., 14 (Box 179)
      Some of these works are also attributed to Adam Elsheimer.
    - Sarto, Andrea del, 1486-1531., 226 (Box 179)
      - Drawings., 62 (Box 179)
        - Studies, figures., 28 (Box 179)
        - Studies, hands., 10 (Box 179)
        - Studies, heads., 24 (Box 180)
      - Paintings., 164 (Box 180)
        - Locations not noted and private collections., 8 (Box 180)
        - Miscellaneous cities., 20 (Box 180)
        - Florence., 107 (Box 180)
          - Miscellaneous locations., 2 (Box 180)
          - S. Annunziata., 25 (Box 181)
          - Pitti., 32 (Box 181-, Box 182)
          - S. Salvi., 10 (Box 182)
          - Chiostro dello Scalzo., 14 (Box 182)
          - Uffizi., 24 (Box 182)
        - London., 6 (Box 182)
        - Madrid., 8 (Box 182)
        - Paris., 5 (Box 182)
        - Rome., 10 (Box 183)
    - Sassetta, 1392-1450., 71 (Box 183)
      Also known as Stefano di Giovanni.
      - Locations not noted., 4 (Box 183)
      - St. Anthony panels., 15 (Box 183)
      - Miscellaneous cities., 34 (Box 183)
      - London., 10 (Box 183)
      - New York., 8 (Box 183)
    - Savoldo, Giovanni Girolamo, c.1480-1550., 19 (Box 183)
    - Schedone, Bartolommeo, 1560-1616., 9 (Box 183)
    - Schiavone, Andrea, active1540-1563., 4 (Box 183)
    - Schiavone, Giorgio, c.1434-c.1505., 5 (Box 183)
      Also known as Giorgio Chiulinovich.
    - Segantini, Giovanni, 1858-1899., 14 (Box 183)
    - Segna di Buonaventura, active 1298-1327., 14 (Box 183)